A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Civil War Commission, 1952-1966 (bulk 1958-1965)
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1956-1966., Extent: 30.8 cu. ft. (Box 1-81d)
  - Publications Files.
    - Iron Gate to the Confederacy: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1960-1963. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - List of Publications (with photographs), 1965. (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Monuments to Memories: Virginia's Civil War Heritage in Bronze and Stone, 1963-1964; undated. (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Monuments to Memories: Accomac - Amelia, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Monuments to Memories: Amherst - Bland, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Monuments to Memories: Botetourt - Buena Vista, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Monuments to Memories: Campbell - Charles City, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Monuments to Memories: Charlottesville - Chesapeake, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Monuments to Memories: Chesterfield, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Monuments to Memories: Clarke - Covington, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Monuments to Memories: Culpeper - Danville, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Monuments to Memories: Dickenson - Falls Church, 1964. (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Monuments to Memories: Fauquier - Floyd, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Monuments to Memories: Fluvanna - Fredericksburg, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Monuments to Memories: Galax - Grayson, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Monuments to Memories: Greene - Harrisonburg, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Monuments to Memories: Henrico - King George, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Monuments to Memories: King and Queen - Loudoun, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Monuments to Memories: Louisa - Lynchburg, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Monuments to Memories: Madison - Mathews, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Monuments to Memories: Mecklenburg - Nelson, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Monuments to Memories: Norfolk, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Monuments to Memories: Northampton - Orange, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Monuments to Memories: Page - Petersburg, 1964. (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Monuments to Memories: Pittsylvania - Prince George, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Monuments to Memories: Princess Anne - Rappahannock, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Monuments to Memories: Richmond City, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Monuments to Memories: Richmond City, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Monuments to Memories: Richmond County - Russell, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Monuments to Memories: Rockingham - Scott, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Monuments to Memories: Shenandoah, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Monuments to Memories: Smyth - Spotsylvania, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Monuments to Memories: Stafford - Virginia Beach, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Monuments to Memories: Warren - Washington, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Monuments to Memories: Waynesboro - Williamsburg, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Monuments to Memories: Winchester, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Monuments to Memories: Wise - York, 1964. (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Museum Directory: Correspondence, 1963-1965. (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Museum Directory: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1963-1965. (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Museum Directory: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1963-1965. (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Museum Directory: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1963-1965. (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Museum Directory: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1963-1965. (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - North Carolina Regimental Histories, 1962. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - North Carolina Regimental Histories, 1962. (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Selected Civil War State Historical Markers, Virginia: Correspondence, 1961-1962. (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Selected Civil War State Historical Markers, Virginia: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1961-1962. (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Military Organizations, A Guide to, 1861-1865: Correspondence, 1963-1965. (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Military Organizations, A Guide to, 1861-1865: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1963-1965. (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Virginia's Decision: Correspondence, 1960-1963. (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Virginia's Decision: Correspondence, 1964-1965. (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Virginia's Decision: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1960-1965. (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1958. (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1959. (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1959. (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1960. (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1960. (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1961. (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1961. (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Correspondence, 1962-1964. (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1958-1961. (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee: Miscellaneous Documentation, 1958-1961. (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Publicity and Tourism.
    - Advertising: Advertising Copy, 1961-1962. (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Advertising: Billboards, 1961-1965. (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Advertising: Centennial Highway Map, 1959-1964. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Advertising: Eastman Kodak Company Advertisements, 1961-1964. (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Advertising: Civil War Commission Trademark Application, 1962. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Advertising: Magazine and Newspaper Advertising, 1963-1964. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Advertising: Motion Pictures, 1959-1962. (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Advertising: Motion Pictures (Related Materials), 1959-1961; undated. (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Advertising: Newspaper Clippings, 1961-1963. (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Advertising: Proofs and Related Correspondence, 1961-1965; undated. (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Advertising: TV and Motion Picture Productions, Inc., 1960-1962. (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - British Travel Association, 1960-1961. (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Centennial Center Publicity, 1960-1962; undated. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Centennial Emblem, 1959-1960. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Centennial Emblem, 1961-1962. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Folders and Window Exhibits, 1961-1962. (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Guided Tour Productions, 1962-1963. (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Ham Radio Awards, 1961-1965. (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - John Marshall Hotel, 1963-1964. (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Magazine Articles and Supporting Documentation, 1960-1961. (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Magazine Articles and Supporting Documentation, 1961-1964. (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Magazine Articles and Supporting Documentation: Notes and Separate Articles, 1961-1962. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Maps, 1960-1964. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Maps, undated. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - News Releases, 1963. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - News Releases, 1964. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - News Releases, 1964. (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - News Releases, 1965. (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper and Television, 1959-1960. (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper and Television, 1960. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper and Television, 1961-1964. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: Publication and Reproduction, 1961-1962. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Public Relations Awards, 1959-1965. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Radio and Television Spots, 1959-1965. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Richmond Public Relations Association, 1959-1966. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Slide Program, 1960-1962. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Sound and Light Program, 1960-1961. (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Speeches Regarding the Virginia Civil War Centennial, 1958-1961. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Speeches Regarding the Virginia Civil War Centennial, 1962. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Television Clips, 1961-1965. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - "The Battle of Songs," by the Arlingtones, 1961. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Tourist Industry Commission, 1964-1965. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Travel Brochures and Virginia Civil War Centennial Hand-outs, 1965; undated. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Travel Industry in Virginia, 1962; undated. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Travel Industry in Virginia, 1963. (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Travel Industry in Virginia, 1964. (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Travel Industry in Virginia, 1965. (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 1958-1960; undated. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 1961. (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 1962-1963. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 1964-1965. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Press Association, 1960-1963. (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Virginia State Fair, 1960-1961. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Virginia State Fair, 1962-1964. (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1958-1959. (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1960. (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1961. (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1962. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1963. (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1963. (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1964. (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Travel Council, 1965. (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Travel Council Awards, 1961-1965. (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - State Agencies.
    - Budget, Division of, 1962-1966. (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, 1961-1966. (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Conservation and Economic Development, Department of, 1959-1960. (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Conservation and Economic Development, Department of, 1961. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Conservation and Economic Development, Department of, 1962. (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Conservation and Economic Development, Department of, 1963. (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Conservation and Economic Development, Department of, 1964-1965. (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Education, Department of, 1959-1960. (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Education, Department of, 1961-1962. (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Education, Department of, 1963-1966. (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Fine Arts, Museum of, 1960-1964. (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Governor, Office of the, 1959-1965. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Highways, Department of, 1961-1965. (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Development, Division of, 1962-1965. (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Jamestown Foundation, 1958-1965. (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Medical College of Virginia, 1961-1966. (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Motor Vehicles, Division of, 1960-1964. (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Purchases and Supply, Department of, 1963-1966. (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - State Agency Group Luncheon, 1961-1962. (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Institute of Marine Science, 1962. (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Military Institute, 1960-1964. (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1961. (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Virginia State Library, 1964-1966. (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - William and Mary, College of, 1960-1965. (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous.
    These four boxes were discovered in 2022. It was unclear where to interfile the papers so a Miscellaneous grouping was created.
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, General. (Box 81a, Folder 1)
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, A-C. (Box 81a, Folder 2)
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, D-F. (Box 81a, Folder 3)
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, G-I. (Box 81a, Folder 4)
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, J-L. (Box 81a, Folder 5)
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, M-N. (Box 81a, Folder 6)
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, O-P. (Box 81b, Folder 1)
    - Civil War background material, Civil War biographies, S-Z. (Box 81b, Folder 2)
    - Civil War background material, Map of Lee's retreat from Richmond, 1953. (Box 81b, Folder 3)
    - Civil War background material, Misc., 1959-1965. (Box 81b, Folder 4-5)
    - Civil War background material, Newsletters, Blue & Gray Notes, 1961. (Box 81b, Folder 6)
    - Civil War background material, Newsletters, Valley News Echo, 1959-1963. (Box 81b, Folder 7)
    - Civil War background material, Newsletters, Valley News Echo, 1963-1965. (Box 81b, Folder 8)
    - Jefferson Davis Inaugural Commemoration, 1962. (Box 81b, Folder 9)
    - Other organizations, Confederates States Centennial Conference, Financial, 1962-1965. (Box 81c, Folder 1-2)
    - Publicity and Tourism, Mailing lists, 1960-1965. (Box 81c, Folder 3)
    - Publicity and Tourism, Travel brochures, A-E, 1960-1965. (Box 81c, Folder 4)
    - Publicity and Tourism, Travel brochures, F-N, 1960-1965. (Box 81c, Folder 5)
    - Publicity and Tourism, Travel brochures, O-U, 1960-1965. (Box 81c, Folder 6)
    - Publicity and Tourism, Travel brochures, R-V, 1960-1965. (Box 81d, Folder 1)
    - Publicity and Tourism, Travel brochures, V-Y, 1960-1965. (Box 81d, Folder 2)
    - Souvenirs, 1960-1965. (Box 81d, Folder 3)
- Series II. Scrapbooks, 1959-1965., Extent: .73 cu. ft and 3 volumes. (Box 82-84)
  Contains three intact scrapbooks and three with the bindings removed. The contents of the unbound scrapbooks are arranged in their original order. The scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings, brochures and other memorabilia associated with the Virginia Civil War Commission, its events and activities. The dates for most of the scrapbooks overlap to some extent.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Scrapbook (Newspaper Clippings: National Releases), 1959-1961. (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook (Newspaper Clippings: General Civil War Period), 1959-1961. (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook (Newspaper Clippings: Letters to the Editor/Editorials), 1959-1961. (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook (Newspaper Clippings: Books and Publications), 1959-1961. (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1960-1965. (Volume 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1965. (Volume 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1965. (Volume 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1964. (Box 83)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1964. (Box 84)
- Series IV. Site Plans and Architectural Drawings, 1960., Extent: .33 cu. ft. (1 oversize folder). (Map-case 9, Drawer 2)
  Contains two site plans/architectural drawings associated with the construction of the Centennial Center in downtown Richmond.
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Civil War Centennial Center Plans, 1960. (Map-case 9, Drawer 2.)
  - Exhibit Floor Plan, undated. (Map-case 9, Drawer 2.)
- Series IV.The Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee, 1959-1961 (photostats and card index: 1832-1870)., Extent: 21 cu. ft. (Box 85-149.)
  Contains photostatic copies of letters and papers assembled by Louis Manarin during his research and compilation of The Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee. This is a large collection of material gathered together from a variety of different institutions. The Robert E. Lee papers date from well before, during, and after the Civil War. Papers featured in the publication are under the heading of "Transcripts" because the files usually contain transcriptions in addition to the photostatic copies. Letters and papers not selected for inclusion in the book are filed under "Unused Letters and Papers," and do not normally include transcriptions. A card index to all of the papers is available. Each entry in the index contains information about a particular document, including where it was located, whether in private hands or in a research institution. Several files and a scrapbook pertaining to the publication process are also found here. The majority of the papers are letters, mostly from General Robert E. Lee, but a few General and Special Orders and circulars are included as well. Lee's correspondents include, among others, his wife, Mary Anna Randolph Custis Lee (often referred to only as "Wife"), his son George Washington Custis Lee (referred to as G.W.C. Lee), his daughters Annie, Agnes, and Mildred, the Honorable James A. Seddon, Confederate Secretary of War (referred to as J.A. Seddon), Stonewall Jackson (referred to as "T.J. Jackson"), Brigadier General John B. Magruder, General Joseph E. Johnston, General J.E.B. Stuart, Jefferson Davis, President of the Confederacy, General James Longstreet, General Braxton Bragg, General Richard Ewell (referred to as R.S. Ewell), General Samuel Cooper (referred to as S. Cooper), General John C. Breckinridge (referred to as J.C. Breckinridge), General P.G.T. Beauregard, and General Ulysses S. Grant. The names found in the content list were taken directly from the original folder headings. Consistency in name formation is somewhat lacking.
  Arranged under four headings: Card Index, Publication Files, Transcripts, and Unused Letters and Papers. The card index is arranged chronologically. The publication files are arranged alphabetically by subject. The letters and papers in the transcript files are individually foldered and arranged by chapter, which is also almost entirely chronological. The unused letters and papers are arranged chronologically as well, but they have not been refoldered or accounted for individually in this finding aid. Researchers should use the card index to reference the unused letters and papers.
  - Card Index to the Papers of Robert E. Lee, 1832-1870.
    - 1832-1861 June 21. (Box 85)
    - 1861 June 22-1862 March 31. (Box 86)
    - 1862 April 1-September 24. (Box 87)
    - 1862 September 25-1863 June 4. (Box 88)
    - 1863 June 5-1864 February 28. (Box 89)
    - 1864 March 1-August 31. (Box 90)
    - 1864 September 1-1865 December 20. (Box 91)
    - 1866-1870. (Box 92)
  - Publication Files, 1959-1961.
    - Confederate Government Officials, undated. (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Depositories: Confederate Museum, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Depositories: Duke University, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Depositories: Emory University, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Depositories: Miscellaneous, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Depositories: North Carolina Department of Archives and History, 1959. (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Depositories: North Carolina, University of, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Depositories: Private Collections, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Depositories: Virginia Historical Society, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Depositories: Virginia State Library, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Depositories: Virginia, University of, 1959-1960. (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Editor's Notes, undated. (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Purchase Orders, 1960-1961. (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook: Publication of War Time Papers of General R.E. Lee, 1961. (Box 93)
    - Source of Letters Edited, 1960. (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Transcripts, 1833-1865.
    - Chapter One.
      - To General Scott, 1861 April 20. (Box 93, Folder 15)
      - To Honorable Simon Cameron, 1861 April 20. (Box 93, Folder 16)
      - To Sister Ann Marshall, 1861 April 20. (Box 93, Folder 17)
      - To Brother Smith, 1861 April 20. (Box 93, Folder 18)
      - To Members of the Virginia Convention, 1861 April 23. (Box 93, Folder 19)
      - General Orders, Number 1, 1861 April 23. (Box 93, Folder 20)
      - To General Daniel Ruggles, 1861 April 24. (Box 93, Folder 21)
      - To "My Dear," 1861 April 25. (Box 93, Folder 22)
      - To Wife, 1861 April 26. (Box 93, Folder 23)
      - To Colonel T.J. Jackson, 1861 April 27. (Box 93, Folder 24)
      - To Governor and Council, 1861 April 27. (Box 93, Folder 25)
      - To Andrew Talcott, Esq., 1861 April 29. (Box 93, Folder 26)
      - To Wife, 1861 April 30. (Box 93, Folder 27)
      - To Major F. Boykin, Jr., 1861 April 30. (Box 93, Folder 28)
      - To Colonel T.J. Jackson, 1861 May 1. (Box 93, Folder 29)
      - To Wife, 1861 May 2. (Box 93, Folder 30)
      - General Orders, Number 10, 1861 May 5. (Box 93, Folder 31)
      - To Colonel P. St. G. Cocke, 1861 May 16. (Box 93, Folder 32)
      - To Colonel T.J. Jackson, 1861 May 6. (Box 93, Folder 33)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1861 May 7. (Box 93, Folder 34)
      - To Colonel W.B. Taliaferro, 1861 May 8. (Box 93, Folder 35)
      - To Colonel T.J. Jackson, 1861 May 9. (Box 93, Folder 36)
      - To Colonel P. St. G. Cocke, 1861 May 10. (Box 93, Folder 37)
      - To Colonel T.J. Jackson, 1861 May 10. (Box 93, Folder 38)
      - To Colonel G.H. Terrett, 1861 May 10. (Box 93, Folder 39)
      - General Orders, Number 14, 1861 May 10. (Box 93, Folder 40)
      - To Wife, 1861 May 11. (Box 93, Folder 41)
      - To General W. Gwynn, 1861 May 12. (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - To Colonel T.J. Jackson, 1861 May 12. (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - To General W. Gwynn, 1861 May 14. (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - To Colonel T.J. Jackson, 1861 May 14. (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - To Colonel G.H. Terrett, 1861 May 15. (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - To Colonel P. St. G. Cocke, 1861 May 15. (Box 94, Folder 6)
      - To Wife, 1861 May 16. (Box 94, Folder 7)
      - To Colonel W.B. Taliaferro, 1861 May 19. (Box 94, Folder 8)
      - To Honorable J.M. Mason, 1861 May 21. (Box 94, Folder 9)
      - To General M.L. Bonham, 1861 May 22. (Box 94, Folder 10)
      - To Colonel G. Porterfield, 1861 May 24. (Box 94, Folder 11)
      - To General M.L. Bonham, 1861 May 24. (Box 94, Folder 12)
      - To General B. Huger, 1861 May 25. (Box 94, Folder 13)
      - To Honorable L. Pope Walker, 1861 May 25. (Box 94, Folder 14)
      - To Wife, 1861 May 25. (Box 94, Folder 15)
      - To Governor Joseph E. Brown (Georgia), 1861 May 26. (Box 94, Folder 16)
      - To General B. Huger, 1861 May 27. (Box 94, Folder 17)
      - To Colonel J.B. Magruder, 1861 May 27. (Box 94, Folder 18)
      - To General J.E. Johnston, 1861 May 27. (Box 94, Folder 19)
      - To Wife, 1861 May 28. (Box 94, Folder 20)
      - To General J.E. Johnston, 1861 May 30. (Box 94, Folder 21)
      - To General J.E. Johnston, 1861 June 1. (Box 94, Folder 22)
      - To General J.E. Johnston, 1861 June 1. (Box 94, Folder 23)
      - To General J.E. Johnston, 1861 June 7. (Box 94, Folder 24)
      - General Orders, Number 25, 1861 June 8. (Box 94, Folder 25)
      - To Wife, 1861 June 9. (Box 94, Folder 26)
      - To General T.H. Holmes, 1861 June 10. (Box 94, Folder 27)
      - To Wife, 1861 June 11. (Box 94, Folder 28)
      - To Colonel G. Porterfield, 1861 June 13. (Box 94, Folder 29)
      - To Colonel J.B. Magruder, 1861 June 13. (Box 94, Folder 30)
      - To Governor John Letcher, 1861 June 14. (Box 94, Folder 31)
      - To Governor John Letcher, 1861 June 15. (Box 94, Folder 32)
      - To Commanding Officer, Yorktown, Virginia, 1861 June 16. (Box 94, Folder 33)
      - To Wife, 1861 June 24. (Box 94, Folder 34)
      - To Mildred Lee, 1861 June 29. (Box 94, Folder 35)
      - To Wife, 1861 July 2. (Box 94, Folder 36)
      - To General J.H. Winder, 1861 July 5. (Box 94, Folder 37)
      - To Colonel J.B. Magruder, 1861 July 5. (Box 94, Folder 38)
    - Chapter Two.
      - To Mrs. Lee, 1861 August 4. (Box 94, Folder 39)
      - To General Henry A. Wise, 1861 August 8. (Box 94, Folder 40)
      - To Wife, 1861 August 9. (Box 94, Folder 41)
      - To General Henry A. Wise (Special Orders, Number 243), 1861 August 21. (Box 94, Folder 42)
      - To General Henry A. Wise, 1861 August 27. (Box 94, Folder 43)
      - To Daughters, 1861 August 29. (Box 94, Folder 44)
      - To Wife, 1861 September 1. (Box 94, Folder 45)
      - To Custis Lee, 1861 September 3. (Box 94, Folder 46)
      - To Wife, 1861 September 9. (Box 94, Folder 47)
      - To General Henry A. Wise, 1861 September 9. (Box 94, Folder 48)
      - Special Orders, Number 7, 1861 September 9. (Box 94, Folder 49)
      - To Wife, 1861 September 17. (Box 94, Folder 50)
      - To Governor John Letcher, 1861 September 17. (Box 94, Folder 51)
      - To General Henry A. Wise, 1861 September 21. (Box 94, Folder 52)
      - To General Henry A. Wise, 1861 September 25. (Box 94, Folder 53)
      - To Wife, 1861 September 26. (Box 94, Folder 54)
      - To Wife, 1861 October 7. (Box 94, Folder 55)
    - Chapter Three.